DANIEL AYALA

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Location: Rancho Cucamonga, CA

Phone: (213) 984-1222 Email: dianix0330@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/daniel-ayala-930330

SUMMARY

An experienced software engineer with 9+ years of experience. Strong experience in entire software development life-cycle, including requirement analysis to design, development, testing, maintenance and documentation. My passion is creating intuitive, efficient, and secure applications that not only meet customers' needs, but also deliver a truly stunning user experience.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER EVRONE

Aug 2020 - Present / San Francisco, CA

- Developed and maintained a high-performance, scalable, and user-friendly Digital Health Platform to ensure applications met the highest standards.
 - Designed and developed a responsive admin panel of a mental health page, using React, Redux, and Tailwind CSS.
 - Utilized Reactivesearch with React to develop a UI powered by Elasticsearch.
 - Implemented infinite scrolling to provide an enhanced user experience.
 - Introduced and executed a testing strategy using Jest and Cypress, which resulted in test coverage of 85% of all client code.
 - Monitored multiple platform components on a rotating on-call basis, quickly identified and resolved critical issues to ensure high availability.
- Developed responsive web pages and dashboards for the Empower internal platform.
 - Created a visualization for displaying real-time data in interactive chart, graph, and table formats using React, and D3.js.
 - Improve website performance by 15% by implementing memoization, code-splitting, and caching techniques.
 - Collaborated with the backend engineering team to ensure a smooth integration of backend services and a seamless user experience.
- Mentored junior developers by helping them to achieve personal goals and professional growth. Technology Used: JavaScript, React, Redux, D3, GraphQL, MySQL, Tailwind CSS, Elasticsearch, Jest, Cypress, NodeJS, Python

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER YELLOW SYSTEMS

May 2018 - Aug 2020 / San Francisco, CA

- Played key role in building project management platform.
 - Developed reusable components with Storybook, leveraging existing components to create complex user interfaces and features.
 - o Utilized Redux-Tool-Kit to manage application state and create seamless UX.
 - Implemented tasteful UI/UX design along with modern and appealing features like dark mode and animation with Framer Motion.

- Lead the front-end engineering team and supervised and managed a dozen developers during the entire development lifecycle.
- o Established the team's accessibility standards and code style guides.
- Designed API endpoints using Node.js.
 - Led the transition from RESTful API to GraphQL by setting up Apollo Server / Client, resulting in improved performance and intuitive developer experience.
 - Used Dgraph and Swagger to document APIs and ensure easy maintenance of endpoints while also leveraging Postman to test and debug APIs.
- Set up CI/CD using Jenkins deploying SPA to AWS and trigger with git.
- Implement Redis for caching, Sentry.io, and Mixpanel for logging issues on production environment and tracking user activities.

Technology Used: JavaScript, React, Redux, GraphQL, REST, AWS S3, Lambda, Jenkins, CI/CD, Redis, Sentry

FULLSTACK ENGINEER MINDGRUB

Nov 2014 - May 2018 / New York, NY

- Refactored code and upgraded legacy online market system to React.
 - Established Redux Thunk and Saga middleware to handle API actions asynchronously for global state management.
 - o Migrate web app from jQuery to React (Material UI + Typescript) to enhanced overall UX.
 - o Partnered with Designers to implement fully responsive UI/UX based on Material-UI, with custom theming, accessibility and internationalization.
 - Wrote unit tests for React components and maintained over 90% test coverage for all of the features.
- Implemented WCAG 2.0 guidelines to improve web accessibility, resulting in a 7% increase in conversion rate.
- Leveraged NodeJS, AWS Lambda + API Gateway, CloudFront to ship RESTful backend APIs on server less environment.
- Worked closely with the business team and product team to design and develop innovative applications and technology.

Technology Used: JavaScript, React Hooks, Redux Thunk, Material UI, WCAG 2.0, AWS SNS, AWS SQS, Webpack, Babel, React Testing Library

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE
COMPUTER SCIENCE
NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF SINGAPORE

09/2010 - 09/2014

- Won the championship in the ICFP (2013)
- GPA: 3.65